I'll start off by calculating how many of the pairs of data points are in
首先 我要计算有多少组数据点
the same direction relative to their respective means.
相对其平均值的方向相同
That is, both above the mean or both below the mean.
也就是 两者都高于或都低于平均值
To do this, I'll first create an array called is_same_direction,
为此 我首先创建名为 is_same_direction 的数组
which contains a boolean for each pair of data points.
其中包含每对数据点的布尔值
Now there are two cases for how the pairs could be in the same direction.
方向相同的数据可以有两种情况
They could either be both above their means or both below their means.
它们可以都高于或都低于平均值
So I'll create two separate arrays of booleans for those two cases.
所以我要针对这两个情况分别创建布尔数组
I can use this code to check whether each value of variable1 is
我可以用这个代码检查 variable1 的每个值
greater than the mean of variable1, and
是否大于 variable1 的平均值
each value of variable2 is greater than the mean of variable2.
以及 variable2 的每个值是否大于 variable2 的平均值
Again make sure you add the parentheses.
与此前一样 一定要加上小括号
It's important to do the comparisons first and then do the logical and.
我们要先进行比较 再进行逻辑运算
The code to check whether both variables are below the mean is identical
检查两个变量是否都低于平均值的代码是一样的
except with less than signs instead of greater than signs.
只是把大于号变成小于号
Then two variables are in the same direction, if they are both above or
然后 若两个变量都大于或都小于其平均值
both below their means.
则两变量的方向相同
Like I mentioned in the instruction video,
我在说明视频中提到过
you can add up an array of booleans to see how many of them were true.
你可以把布尔数组的值加总 以查看真值的数量
So I can find the number of pairs that are in the same direction by calculating
所以 我可以通过 is_same_direction.sum()
is the same direction dot sum.
计算方向相同的组数
Finally, I can calculate nom different direction by taking the len of variable
最后 我可以通过 variable1 的长度 减去方向相同的组数
one minus the number of pairs in the same direction.
计算出 num_different_direction
Last, I'll need to return the two numbers.
最后 我需要返回这两个数字
Now if you ran this function for the life expectancy and GDP arrays given in
如果你针对编程练习中的预期寿命和 GDP 数据运行这个函数
the programming exercise, you should have seen that there were 17 pairs that
你应该看到 有 17 对数据方向相同
went in the same direction, and three that went in different directions.
方向相反的数据有 3 对
The fact that most of the pairs went in the same direction indicates that these
大部分数据的方向相同
two variables are positively correlated.
说明这两个变量是正相关
That is, when one is higher, the other tends to be higher as well.
也就是 当一个值较大 另一个值也会较大
If the first number had been small, and the second number had been large,
若第一个数字变小 第二个数字变大
that would indicate that the variables are negatively correlated.
这说明变量是负相关
When one tends to be large, the other tends to be small.
当一个值变大 另一个往往会变小
And if the two numbers had been roughly equal,
如果两个数字大致相等
then that indicates that there might not be a strong relationship.
那说明两者没有太大关联
It's about equally likely for
两个变量的关系属于
one variable to be positively correlated with the other as negatively correlated.
正相关和负相关的可能性是相同的